the Bible says then certain of the
scribes and of the Pharisees answered
saying master we would see a sign from
thee but he answered and said unto them
an evil and adulterous generation
seeketh after a sign and there shall no
sign be given to it but the sign of the
Prophet Jonas pause for a second Jesus
here speaking says an evil and
adulterous generation seeks a sign is
that a good thing or a bad things that
sound like Jesus is saying something
that is good or something that is bad
right an evil and adulterous generation
seeks after a sign and yet the Bible
continues on because Jesus says that
they will actually receive a sign that
they actually do receive a sign and that
sign according to verse 39 is the sign
of the prophet Jonah verse 44 s Jonah
was three days and three nights in the
whales belly so shall the Son of Man be
three days and three nights in the heart
of the earth the men of Nineveh shall
rise up in judgment with this generation
and shall condemn it because they
repented at the preaching of Jonah and
behold a greater than Jonah is here the
Queen of the South shall rise up in
judgment with this generation and shall
condemn it for she came from the
uttermost parts of the earth to hear the
wisdom of Solomon and behold a greater
than Solomon is here Jesus does not draw
these two stories just out of a hat
somewhere he speaks of the story of
Jonah and then he speaks of the story of
the Queen of the south anyone know who
that is
the Queen of Sheba so on one hand he is
addressing the story of Jonah and his
Jurnee here's what everyone his journey
to where Nineveh and then on the other
hand he addresses the Queen of Sheba and
her journey somewhere now who knows
where she bowing where the Queen of
Sheba went where did she go
who does she go to see she went to see
Solomon and what city did she go to
Jerusalem very good
so here Jesus takes two stories two
journeys one of Jonah to Nineveh one of
the Queen of Sheba to Jerusalem and he
couples these stories together and
beloved there's a reason why he does
this want you to notice this with me the
sign that Jesus said would be given to
the evil and adulterous generation how
many of you would probably agree with me
that we are living in an evil and
adulterous generation yeah and even
though Jesus when he was speaking was
speaking specifically of a generation
that he was in because they were the
generation that would receive this sign
of Jonah three days and three nights in
the in the belly of the fish we are
still in an evil and adulterous
generation and I want to suggest to you
that the sign is still the same sign the
sign for this generation this evil and
adulterous generation is the same sign
that it was when Jesus spoke at almost
2,000 years ago it is still the death
burial and resurrection of Jesus Christ
the greatest sign we can give to an evil
and adulterous generation is listen
carefully it is not the prophecy of
revelation 13 or Daniel 7 or any of
those other prophecies the greatest sign
that we can give to an evil and
adulterous generation to lead them to
believe and be prepared for the coming
of Jesus is the death burial and
resurrection of Jesus Christ in fact I
believe that this sign is
is so great that all our the signs point
to this sign all other signs given in
the Bible is given so that we may
believe that Jesus died was buried and
resurrected again as the scripture says
Paul in 1st Corinthians chapter 1 verse
22 writes this for the Jews require a
sign and the Greeks seek after wisdom
but we preach Christ Watts crucified
unto the Jews a stumbling-block and
foolishness or and unto the Greeks
foolishness but unto them which are
called both Jews and Greeks Christ the
power and wisdom of God the Bible tells
us here that Christ crucified Christ
dead buried and resurrected is the
wisdom of God Paul said there is nothing
greater than the preaching of this
message Christ and him crucified it is
the wisdom of God notice with me John
chapter 14 verse 29 you will go through
these verses rapidly and then we're
going to go over to the Book of Jonah
but I want you to notice with me John
chapter 14 verse 29 and 30 Jesus
speaking here says and now I have told
you before it come to pass that when it
come to pass you might want believe
hereafter I will not talk much with you
for the prince of this world cometh and
has nothing in me now what was Jesus
talking about here what did he mean when
he said hereafter I will not talk with
you much what was about to happen to him
he was about to be killed he was about
to be crucified
but Jesus connects prophecy with that
very thing he says behold I tell you
before we come to pass that when it
comes to pass
you might believe what that I am he let
me suggest to you that all the
prophecies of Daniel and all the
prophecies of Revelation are geared
towards one thing for us to believe that
Jesus died was buried and rose again the
third day because that is the greatest
sign see all these other prophecies are
given to us so that we can believe God
amen God says I want you to believe me
believe what believe that my son came
died and rose again well why would I
believe that well let me give you
prophecy to show you that what I say is
true so as you see prophecies unfold it
is designed to strengthen our
understanding and our belief that Jesus
Christ died was buried and rose again
prophecy strengthens our faith in the
death burial and resurrection of Jesus
Christ so let's go to this story I want
you to turn with me to the Book of Jonah
and we're going to go to Jonah chapter 1
The Book of Jonah chapter 1 Jonah
chapter 1 the Bible says now the word of
the Lord came unto Jonah the son of
amitayus saying arise go to Nineveh that
great city and cry against it for their
wickedness is come up before me now ask
you a question how wicked do you think
the city of Nineveh was pretty bad
pretty bad that God says to Jonah I need
you to go and I need you to warn this
city so we might think of Nineveh as a
wicked or sinful City and God has called
Jonah to
go and preach against this city
NASA question how do you think God feels
about Nineveh saying in not very good
all right
concerned sad disconnected does God is
Nineveh and evil and adulterous
generation does God love that evil and
adulterous generation how do we know God
loves that evil and adulterous
generation because he sends Jonah to
that evil and adulterous generation
because he wants that evil and
adulterous generation to want to repent
for God so loved the world right that He
gave His only begotten Son so we know
how God feels about this even though
there and there are evil and adulterous
generation God is about to send Jonah
verse three but Jonah rose up to flee on
to Tarshish from the presence of the
Lord and went down to Joppa and he found
the ship going to Tarshish so he paid
the fare thereof and went down into it
to go with them on to Tarshish from the
presence of the Lord now Jonah decided
that he is not going to obey God I have
a question for you
why I'm here in a hole
the answers here why does jonah decide
i'm not even going to go to nineveh all
right let me let me ask you this way
let's say that you know you lived
outside of the Bay Area and then someone
said to you hey we're gonna pay you to
go evangelize the Bay Area many of you
might say that Bay Area are you serious
that area is so secular that area is is
so far from having God on their minds
all they're about is money like they're
not going to hear my message do you
think so what's going through Jonah's
mind this city is so wicked that they
will not hear me if I were to go
it's as if Jonah has written off this
wicked city and so you know the story
Jonah goes down into the ship but the
Bible says in verse 4 but the Lord sent
out a great wind into the sea and there
was a mighty tempest in the sea so that
the ship was like to be broken and the
Mariners were afraid and and and tried
every man unto his Prater criterion
which was God and cast forth the wares
that were in the ship into the sea to
lighten it of them but Jonah was gone
down into the sides of the ship and he
lay and was fast asleep and you know the
story right these men are terrified
because this storm has come by the way
God brought the storm God brought this
stone because Jonah was going against
the will of God and so God brings this
mighty wind and the people start start
crying out to their gods
got their gods are not answering and
then they find Jonah asleep in the
bottom of the ship and they go to him
and they say who are you and Jonah tells
them who he is and then Jonah says
listen this is my fault this is
happening because of me and they say to
Jonah well what should we do
and I want you to check this out jump
down with me to verse 16 verse rather
verse verse 11 they said unto Him what
shall we do unto thee that the sea may
be calm unto us and this for the sea
wrought and was tempestuous and he
summoned to them take me up and cast me
forth into the sea so shall the sea be
common to you for I know that from my
sake this great tempest is upon you
verse 16 then the men feared or verse 15
so they took up Jonah and cast him forth
into the sea and the sea ceased from her
raging then the men feared the Lord
exceedingly and offered a sacrifice unto
the Lord and made vows now the Lord had
prepared a great fish to swallow up
Jonah and Jonah was in the belly of the
fish three days and what three nights
Jonah is thrown overboard and as soon as
he is thrown overboard
something happens tell me what happens
the seas are calm let me speak to you
for a moment
you see Jonah being thrown overboard
would have ensured his what his his
death this was a raging storm not a
question for you how many of you ever
experienced a raging storm in your life
how many of you know what it's like to
go through those raging storms listen
carefully when Jonah was thrown
overboard remember Jesus said of himself
that Jonah was a type of himself I want
to say
that Jesus's death brings the calm to
our storms Jesus when he died his death
let me say this way many of us ride the
storm of life without Direction fearful
and when Jesus comes into the life when
we accept his death burial and
resurrection that has power to calm the
storms I can look back at my life before
Jesus entered and it was a stormy life
it was a it was a stormy path but once I
accepted Christ into my life guess what
his death burial and resurrection calm
the storms how many of you remember the
story where Jesus is on the ship with
the disciples and he is sleeping and
remember how the Bible says this storm
came upon the waters and and they were
all terrified just like the story of
Jonah and they go and wake Jesus up they
say do you not care that we perish and
Jesus looks at the man he says o ye of
what little faith and he stands up and
he says peace be still peace be still
and beloved when he said those words the
waters were calmed listen to me the
storms of life can be totally
overwhelming but Jesus
says I am come listen check us out guys
Jonah went on a journey is that right
he worked not at first his journey was
away from Nineveh but we're going to see
the story that God eventually convinces
Jonah that his journey should be towards
Nineveh praise God that Jesus did not
need to be convinced to come to us he
did not run away from the will of God as
Jonah did nonetheless he uses Jonah as a
type of himself the death of Jesus calms
the storms that we're in Jesus says come
unto me all ye that labor and are heavy
laden and I will give you what rest
Psalm 107 verse 28 says this then they
cried to the Lord in their trouble and
he bringeth them out of their
de-stresses he maketh the storm a calm
so that the waves thereof are still then
are they glad because they be quiet so
he bringing them unto their desired
Haven Jesus is a master of calming the
storms in John 14 verse 27 Jesus said
peace I leave with you my peace I give
unto you not as the world giveth give I
unto you let not your heart be troubled
neither let it be afraid Jesus is
telling us listen despite the storms
going around you know that the cause I
came and died for you that I will carry
you safely through the storm this is
what Jesus came to do so
Jonah is swallowed up by this fish in
Jonah chapter 2 Jonah chapter 2 verse 10
after Jonah spends three days in the
belly of this fish the Bible says in the
Lord spake unto the fish and it vomited
out Jonah onto the dry land three days
Jonah spent
in the belly of this fish Jonah chapter
3 verse 1 and the word of the Lord came
unto Jonah the second time saying arise
go unto Nineveh that great city and
preach unto it the preaching that I bid
thee so Jonah arose and went onto
Nineveh according to the word of the
Lord
now Nineveh was an exceeding great city
of three day's journey and Jonah began
to enter into the city a day's journey
and he cried and said yet forty days and
Nineveh shall be overthrown let me ask
you a question do you think Jonah just
had a rough three days do you think it
was a pretty pretty rough three days the
Bible says after these three days God
called this this fish to vomit Jonah out
so Jonah
rises up out of the water
now I want you to think about this the
men that had thrown him over believe
that he was one that he was dead
he is down there underwater for how many
days three days and then he is root he
is brought up out of the water and
listen carefully the Bible says that he
spoke among them that 40 days the city
would be overthrown let me ask you a
question does that picture look familiar
to you do you remember that Jesus Christ
who himself was dead buried and
resurrected on the third day appeared
among his people how many days 40 days
40 days and I want you to understand his
love you see this three day journey of
Jonah to Nineveh to the wicked city was
a treacherous journey and yet Jonah
because of his experience with God was
willing to take it let me ask you a
question was Jesus
journey to the grave a treacherous
journey yeah do you think it was a
journey that none of us ourselves would
want to go through do you look at his
trial just before his death burial and
resurrection and seeing what Jesus went
through on the cross do you think that
that journey was something that no other
human being has ever experienced and yet
beloved in jesus's mind the journey was
worth it the journey was worth it three
days journey and it was worth it why
because God so what loved the world that
He gave His only begotten Son the
journey was worth it why come back with
me
I want to talk to you about the men of
Nineveh remember we've just seen that
Nineveh was a wicked City exceedingly
wicked it was an evil and adulterous
generation it was so wicked that Jonah
himself thought yeah there's no use to
go preach the gospel to this city have a
question for you if Jonah is a type of
Jesus who are the men of Nineveh if
Jonah is a type of Jesus who goes on
this journey to reach the hearts of that
evil and adulterous generation who is
that evil and adulterous generation who
is who are the men of Nineveh a type of
us they love listen to me do you have
you ever looked at yourself and thought
to yourself man there's no hope for me
whoa like like just kind of like Jonah
treated Nineveh do you ever feel like
man I am so messed up inside
I really don't know if there's any hope
for me I don't know if I can be reached
look at all this evil within me look at
all this this wickedness within me I
don't know if God loves me enough to
redeem me beloved let me tell you
something if God loved the wicked and
evil generation back then he loves the
wicked and evil generation right now if
you look at yourself and say man no one
knows what I did last week no one knows
what I did the week before and if people
only knew they would not love me or God
would not love me let me tell you the
journey of Jesus Christ for three days
and three nights in the grave
demonstrates how much God loves the evil
and adulterous generation and yeah I
know that sounds crazy God doesn't love
the evil and adulterous generation no no
no God loves the evening zealous
generation he doesn't love the evil or
adultery but he loves the evil and
adulterous generation and that's why he
gives them the sign come notice with me
again same chapter Jonah chapter 3 verse
5 the Bible says so the people of
Nineveh believed God thank you believed
God and proclaimed the fast and put on
sackcloth from the greatest of them even
to the least of them for the word came
unto the king of Nineveh and he arose
from his throne and he laid his roll
from him and covered him with sackcloth
and sat in ashes and caused it to be
proclaimed and published through Nineveh
by the decree of the king and his nobles
saying let neither man nor beast heard
nor flock taste anything let them not
feed nor drink water but let man and
beast be covered with sackcloth and
crime Mardy unto God yay let them turn
everyone from his evil way and for
the violence that have been in their
hands who can tell if God will turn and
repent and turn away from his fierce
anger that we perish not have a question
for you how wicked was this city how
weak it was this city so do you think
that Jonah going into the city and
saying repent would have all of a sudden
changed this wicked and adulterous City
I mean I want you to think about that
what led the king and the entire city to
be like we need to repent what do you
think led them to that what sign what a
man coming up out of the sea let me ask
you a question if you're sitting on the
beach one day just hanging out you know
yeah what a beautiful day and you've
been there for like hours just enjoying
the Sun and then you see a man walking
up out of the water first of all if you
did not die from fear then the man said
I'm from God and I have a message for
you
God is going to destroy this city do you
think the people of the city might
listen yeah listen carefully beloved
that sign of Jonah was given to the
Ninevites now we don't know how they
know because we're not we're not told it
could have been the people on the ship
there was a strong wind that was blowing
that ship and guess what that strong
wind could have blown that in the
opposite direction from which it was
going I'm sending you back to Nineveh we
have no idea it could have been the
people on the ship it could have been
someone on the shore but somehow or
another they knew that this man named
Jonah
was not any old ordinary preacher he had
just had a very serious life-and-death
experience and when the city cites the
Bible tells us the entire city repented
listen to me beloved the Bible says it
is the goodness of God that leads to
repentance I want you to check this out
beloved God was working out the
salvation of a wicked generation when
they didn't even know what was going on
think about that for a moment Jonah is
out at sea the wicked and evil and
adulterous generation have no idea that
Jonah's coming they have no idea what's
going on with Jonah but God so loved the
wicked and adulterous generation that
out at sea
he's like Jonah no no no no we're gonna
get this right that to me is
mind-blowing when you're over there
messing up God is orchestrating your
salvation he is orchestrating events and
working things out in a way that you are
not even aware of in order to try to
save your evil and wicked self God loves
you and the journey of Jonah is to
demonstrate how much God loves you that
journey that three-day journey was worth
it
God has used for you don't ever think of
yourself as no good cut off beyond hope
beyond help that's what Jonah thought
yeah Nineveh no hope no use cut off
beyond help but that was not the case
beloved because as long as you have
breath God wants to use you as long as
you have breath God can turn you around
God can turn God can calm your storms
your storms God can bring
you into newness of life so I want you
to check this out
because in Matthew 12 verse 41 the Bible
says the men of Nineveh shall rise in
judgment with this generation and shall
condemn it because they repented at the
preaching of Jonas and behold a greater
than Jonah is here so what is Jesus
saying here the men of Nineveh shall do
what what shall the men of Nineveh do
they saw what they saw what everyone
they shall rise in what all right what
is that talking about can someone tell
me what Jesus means when he said the men
of Nineveh shall rise rise in judgment
what's he talking about he's talking
about what resurrection so Jesus saying
listen guess who's going to be
resurrected who the men of Nineveh wait
that the same men of Nineveh that
represent that evil and wicked
adulterous generation yes you and I at
one time or maybe even now guess what
are or were the men of Nineveh and God
says listen the very ones who you
thought were written off the very ones
who you thought there's no hope for them
the very ones who you thought yeah God
really doesn't like them the most very
ones the men of Nineveh because of the
sign of Jonah's of Jesus because they
repented at the death burial and or
because of the death burial and
resurrection of Jesus they will rise in
what in what not now check this out
remember when Jonah got mad when God
like didn't destroy the city and God
said what do you want me to destroy a
city of people who cannot discern
between the right hand and
left what is that word discern mean
wasn't mean to discern you can discern
something you can what you can judge it
check the saga guess who rises in the
judgment the very people who at one time
didn't even know enough to judge
correctly that's you that's me
the very people who at one time could
not tell the difference between right
and wrong Jesus say they are the very
ones that are going to rise in the
judgments why because they feared the
Lord and the Bible says the fear of the
Lord is the beginning of wisdom they got
wise
what is Wisma how do we get wisdom what
did Paul say wisdom was the preaching of
Christ crucified that is the wisdom of
God and so when they repented because of
the wisdom of God they in essence gained
the wisdom of God therefore beloved it
is the men of Nineveh who go forth with
this message fear God and give glory to
him for the hour of his judgment is come
and worship Him that made heaven the
earth in the sea and the font of water
the men of Nineveh preachers message
because they know what it's like to be
redeemed they have had an experience
with the death burial and resurrection
of Jesus Christ they know what it is to
repent because that message is what led
them to repentance they have the wisdom
of God so the question is how do we get
the wisdom of God the Bible tells us in
proverbs 4 verse 5 that we are to get
wisdom and with all our wisdom get
understanding get wisdom and depart from
evil because that is understanding our
goal is how many of you would like
wisdom the next is how many of you have
wisdom right now okay nobody was really
a man okay guys that's not a trick
question okay when you gave your life to
Christ you got wisdom amen that's why
that's a wise decision so how many of
you have wisdom all right but still
you're still cuddly why because we don't
have all the wisdom we really want do we
we wish we were wise all right all right
in this opening text we read Jesus not
only talked about Jonah and his journey
to Nineveh but he also talked about the
Queen of Sheba and her journey to
Jerusalem to speak to Solomon so so
check this out
how many of you know know the story of
Solomon remember how God said to David
David your hands are bloody so you are
not gonna be able to build the house of
God but your son he will build a house
all right so Solomon was came upon the
scene with a very specific purpose to
build build what the house of God all
right that's one thing about Solomon but
here's something else about Solomon you
remember that God comes to Solomon -
Solomon ask what you will and what did
Solomon asked for he asked for wisdom to
do what to judge so check this out
Solomon's position was one who would
build a house of God and whom judgment
was given to all right so check didn't
live follow me carefully Solomon builds
the house of God and he is also given
wisdom to what to judge judgment is
given unto him now how many of you know
how long it took for Solomon to build
the house of God to finish his building
project took about 20 years
and you'll find that come with me second
chronicles second chronicles chapter
eight and you got to see this but of it
is this is this is amazing second
chronicles chapter eight second
chronicles
after 8 and verse 1 it came to pass at
the end of 20 years wherein solomon had
built the house of the lord and his own
house now jump down with me to verse
verse 15 verse 16 now all the work of
solomon was was prepared unto the day of
the foundation of the house of the lord
until it was finished so the house of
the lord was perfect was perfected pause
for a second did Jesus say to his
disciples just before his death burial
and resurrection did he say in John 14 I
go to what prepare a place for you and
if I go I will do what come again and
receive you unto myself that where I am
there you may be also what was Jesus's
mission when he went to heaven to
prepare a place okay where is a place of
Solomon prepared where is this where is
the he prepared the temple but where was
it in Jerusalem right and what is drusen
called
what is the name of Jerusalem I mean
what does Jerusalem mean the city of
city of peace now remember David was a
body man so he could not build the city
the city had to built on to be built on
the one who had a reign of what a reign
of peace let me ask you a question when
Jesus goes to heaven what is his mission
to build a place for us where is that
place he's building the New Jerusalem
amen and when that New Jerusalem is
finished what's going to happen he's
gonna come to take us where he is
okay watch these watches second
chronicles chapter 8 verse 9 or verse 16
we just read that the place is finished
second chronicles chapter 8 verse 16 so
the house of the Lord was perfected now
notice this verse 17 you got verses
17 after 16 right then he got verse 18
after 17 and then you have chapter 9
verse 1 the Bible says in verse 1 and
when the Queen of Sheba heard of the
fame of Solomon she what came okay hold
on a second
Jonah what did he do he journeyed to win
Nineveh which was what kind of a city
wicked City Sheba the Queen of Sheba
what does she do
she journeys where's she turning to
Jerusalem which is what city of peace
why is she going when does she
when does this Queen listen carefully
guys when does this Queen go to
Jerusalem when it's one when it is
finished so the Queen goes Jerusalem
when the when the project is totally
done okay no no no the Queen goes to
Jerusalem when everything that Solomon
has put his hand to is completed is that
correct
why is she going to Jerusalem here
second chronicles chapter nine verse one
the Queen of Sheba heard of the famous
of Solomon that came and she she came to
prove Solomon with what hard questions
pause for a second how many of you have
hard questions how do you have hard
questions you have hard questions for
God how many of you have hard questions
for God Chris is where you're like man
I'm kind of afraid to ask God that one
because I don't know how he's gonna
answer because I really really really
really really need convincing on this
one how many of you would like to ask
God those questions no no you ask him
now but it's kind of like you know how
many of you would like to personally ask
him those questions
how many would personally like to speak
to the wisest man that ever lived and
his name is not Salomon guess when we
get to speak to this why this man that
ever lived when it is what when what's
finished the house that he is building
listen to me guys Jonah went to Nineveh
so that the Queen of Sheba could go to
Jerusalem I just spoke cold just now I
don't know if you can't call what I just
said
Jonah went to Nineveh translate for me
Jesus
came to this wicked world so that Sheba
the Queen of Sheba could journey to
Jerusalem why does the Queen of Sheba
want to go to Jerusalem because she's
got questions hard questions why did
this happen God why did you allow this
to take place how come you know our
questions the questions we all have the
questions we all wish we could ask God
face to face what why got fire why did
everything turn down no why was I born
with this issue I don't get it Lord
that's a riddle to me I don't get it
check this out guys the Queen of Sheba
had hard questions I don't know if you
catch a significance of that how many of
you think all of life's problems would
be solved if I could be a queen or a
king the Queen of Sheba had hard
questions do you think she may have gone
through some things in her life even
being the Queen we can try to act like
we have it all together and oh yeah I'm
good I'm good but beloved all of us have
questions and check the song the Solomon
of heaven says don't worry about it one
day I'm gonna answer those questions for
you when the millennium comes when I
have finished building the house that I
want to prepare I'm going to invite my
church my bride to come and you can ask
me any question you want
beloved listen to me for the queen of
sheba that alone was worth the journey
wait you mean I get to meet Solomon and
talk to him face to face
alright let's go listen to me listen
what it says second chronicles chapter 9
verse 2 verse 1 latter part of verse 1
and when she was come to Solomon she
communed with him of all that was in her
heart how many of you like what you just
read just now she commune with him with
all that was in her heart how do you
understand what I'm saying to you right
now
you get to meet God face-to-face and
commune with him now I want you to
notice the relationship between Jonah
and the Ninevites what kind of
relationship did it feel like
did it seem like it just seemed I kind
of quick he came and he's gone and you
know man I would have sure like to see
in this prophet myself but it just seems
kind of like a a relationship that
wasn't really able to like you know
really reform but what's do what is a
difference between the relationship with
Solomon and the Queen of Sheba we're
going to come
beloved I believe it's like God telling
us listen I know how you feel now you
kind of feel like I'm like a Jonah to
you I'm just telling you to repent and
I'm it may feel like you know Lord where
are you when I need you in and you're
just telling me to repent and it doesn't
feel like you really care about what I'm
going through you're just in and out you
came here thirty three and a half years
and you're gone and now all we have is
the is the recollection or the memory or
these words but but the love of the time
is coming where as a bride like a bride
groom and a bride Jesus is gonna take
his church and say now everything you
always wanted to understand everything
you always wanted to know come on let's
talk let's talk and beloved that is
worth that alone is worth or do you
think it might have been a treacherous
journey for the Queen of Sheba jesus
said that she came from the uttermost
parts of the earth what that means no
one's really sure it was a long journey
and I'm sure they may have been things
on the way that were perilous in that
journey but compare that journey with
the journey of Jonah
compare that trying to compare our
journey to the city of Jerusalem to God
to Jesus's journey to this earth to
redeem us beloved his journey to us made
it possible for us to journey to him
let me read these verses and I want I
want you to see these verses through the
lens that we just put on verse two
Solomon told her all her questions and
there was nothing hid from Solomon which
he told her not and when the Queen of
Sheba had seen the wisdom of Solomon and
the house that he had built are you
following me and the meat at his table
are you following me
and the sitting of his ain't I mean
servants are you following me and the
attendants of his ministers and they're
up
arrow are you following me his
cupbearers also and their apparel and
his ascent by which he went up into the
house of the Lord there was no more
spirit in her I liked how - I like how
how they put that like she fainted like
she was a sigh huh she could not hold a
hand any longer no more spirit within
her but love and listen to me you know
what you know what she says how do you
remember what she says we gotta read
this verse 6 verse 6 verse 5 and she
said to the king it was a true report
which I heard in my own land of dine
acts and of thy wisdom howbeit I believe
not their words until I came and my eyes
had seen it and behold the one-half of
the greatness of thy wisdom was not told
me for thou exceedance the fame that I
heard see beloved we're like the Queen
of Sheba right now we hear about Jesus
oh Jesus did all these wonderful things
and we read about him and we're going
man this is great this is great but let
me tell you something beloved that half
has not been told see we believe now we
yeah I got it I get it but you know when
we see him face to face our response
will be well I has not seen nor ear
heard the things which God has prepared
for them we're gonna say well I did I
underestimated that half has not been
told but we will only say that when we
see it with our own eyes beloved let me
tell you
the journey is worth it the journey is
worth it
Jesus put those two verses together
he says Jonah the the the men of Nineveh
will rise up in this judgment why
because they repented the Queen of Sheba
will rise up in the judgment
she journeyed to hear the wisdom of
Solomon and one greater than Solomon is
here beloved I am looking forward to it
I am looking forward to that sitting
down with the Solomon of heaven how
about you are you looking forward is the
journey worth it that's the question we
all have to answer